Ashish Surana

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

📞 (+91) 978 487 8727 | 🖂 ashishsurana.in@gmail.com | 🏕 ashishsurana.in | 🖸 ashishsurana | in ashishsurana

"Programs must be written for people to read, and only incidentally for machines to execute"

Dear Recruiting Team,

This is regarding the position offered by you as a Front end developer. I'm working as a Software Development Engineer (Front end) at Innovaccer Analytics, Noida (a healthcare product based company). I am looking for an opportunity where I can work in a highly dynamic environment, practice design patterns along with test driven development.

As per my past 2 years of professional experience, I have been able to learn how to write composable and readable code in cross-functional teams, improve legacy code and implement best practices. My passion for programming started when I was introduced to computer science during my Higher Secondary Education. As per Job Description and my experience, I can be a good fit in System One. However, Following are my skills in brief:

- Proficient in Javascript, React, Redux and Node.Js
- Familiarity with **Webpack**, npm, Release Management (**Semver**)
- Open source contributor to **Verdaccio**
- Relevant experience with REST APIs, GraphQL, MongoDB, AWS and DigitalOcean

I have also worked with AadhaarAPI.com, ParkZap and Wisflux as a Software Development Engineer and contributed to SAAS and IOT Products. With my determination, passion for software development and the ability to adapt to new situations, I believe I am a good candidate as a Front end Developer at your company.

Please find the resume and Kindly let me know if you need any more information. Looking forward to hearing from you.

Thanks Regards
Ashish Surana
Software Engineer - Javascript
Contact: +91-9784 878727

Ashish Surana

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

、 (+91) 978 487 8727 | ☑ ashishsurana.in@gmail.com | 🔏 ashishsurana.in | 🤉 ashishsurana | in ashishsurana1

Summary _

I am a software development engineer with 2 years of experience in Fron-tend Development and Javascript, Currently working as a Front-end Engineer at Innovaccer. The challenges of scaling and improving User Interface is my motivation for learning new things. I am always driven to deliver great User Experience and writing clean, composable & readable code.

Skills _____

Current Focus Javascript (ES6), Design Patterns, Functional programming

Libraries - React, Redux, Apollo

Frameworks - AngularJS, Angular, Express, Node.Js

Typed Systems - Typescript, Flow

Also Working with MongoDB, GraphQL, Amazon Web Services, DigitalOcean

Packaging - Webpack, Docker **Automation** - Gitlab CI

Release Management - NPM & Semver

Certifications Red Hat Certified System Admin (RHCSA)

Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE)

Experience _

Innovaccer Analytics Noida, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - I

January 2018 - PRESENT

- About Innovaccer Innovaccer is a **healthcare** data activation platform which provides solutions for care management, referral management, and patient engagement. The Product consist of a **Micro Front-end application** and my roles are as follows:
- Responsible for core framework (Back-end For Front-end) on which other app modules are running
- Contributed in migration of whole Application from monolith architecture to mirco front-end, a modular application architecture
- Actively involved in cross team communication with Designers, Product owners, other developers to take the product forward. I am also maintaining internal private npm registry using verdaccio and CI for smooth collaboration
- Technologies React, AngularJs, Express, Server Side Rendering

AadhaarApi.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - I

Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- About AdhaarAPI Aadhaar is the database containing biometrics 1.3 Billion Indians and AadhaarAPI is a product to leverage the power by developing SDKs over it. I worked on the back-end for the "Know Your Customer (EKYC)" using aadhaar APIs
- Ownership of End to End Release of Dashboard from scratch
- Created efficient REST APIs for improving workflows
- Responsible for bugs, features, deployments, and managing infrastructure
- Technologies Angular, Server Side Rendering, Node.js, Postgres, AWS

Wisflux Edtech Labs

Jaipur, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - INTERN

Jan. 2017 - March 2017

- About Wisflux Wisflux is an edtech startup, developing product to manage teaching content efficiently. While working, I was introduced to Angular and my roles were:
- To develop **REST APIs** and Interface designing in Angular with redux
- To Deliver an AWS Lambda Service from scratch
- Technologies Angular, GraphQL, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS

MAY 18, 2019 ASHISH SURANA · RESUME 1

Projects

Datashop Engine (Innovaccer)

- Datashop-Engine, a Backend for Frontend framework developed to take care of the connection points between existing popular frameworks like Angular, React, Mithril based applications. It is designed to give you a quick and organised way to start developing Datashop based web apps
- Everything in Datashop is a package and when need arises for extending Datashop-Engine with custom functionality, developers can do so creating their own package and do not need to alter the core packages.

Incore (Innovaccer)

- This App is the part of datashop and tightly coupled with core framework. This module take care of all **Role-based Access Control** across the Product. I'm the SPOC for this Module and responsible for all the planning, execution and release of this module
- Technology: AngularJs, React, Express

Open Source ____

Verdaccio

- A Open Source lightweight private npm proxy registry. My contribution was solving bugs, improving test cases, and discussing the feature developments
- Technology: Nodejs, ReactJs, npm, Webpack, Enzyme
- Link: github.com/verdaccio/verdaccio

Education

Rajasthan Technical University

Kota, India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING

June 2017

Vivekananda Kendra Vidyalaya (CBSE)

Bhilwara, India

HIGHER SECONDARY EDUCATION

May 2013

Participations _____

JSFoo Bangalore, India

OCT. 2018

Attended jsfoo, a javascript conference covering the road ahead in JavaScript and the Web ecosystem, Functional programming Improving per
formance and UX, Building systems, tools and processes for teams, Case studies of Vue.js, GraphQL, ReasonML and other framework/language
adoption.

ARCHITECTING ON AWS

Noida, India

SEPT 2018

Completed one week AWS training on architecting on AWS which includes cloud computing, serverless architecture (lambda), efficient architecture and load balancing.